Guide to the Robert Penn Warren Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1930-85; Series II; 60; (145 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Poems
      - "Nocturne": typescript, n.d. (Box 227, Folder 4164)
      - "A Noise Like Memory": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, 1984 (Box 227, Folder 4165)
      - "Not Quite Like a Top": holograph, typescript and carbon, and printed text, [1978] (Box 227, Folder 4166)
      - "Not Until": holograph and typrscript, 1984 (Box 227, Folder 4167)
      - "Notch in the Mountains": holograph and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1984 (Box 227, Folder 4168)
      - "Notes on a Life to Be Lived": setting typescipt, 1966 Feb 12 (Box 227, Folder 4169)
      - "October Picnic, Long Ago": holograph; typescript and carbon, corrected; and photocopy of printed text, 1978 (Box 227, Folder 4170)
      - "Off to College in Old Times": holograph and typescripts, corrected (various states, with duplicates), [1983] (Box 227, Folder 4171)
      - "Oh, Anima": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1976 (Box 227, Folder 4172)
      - "Old Blind Spaniel" (marked "first Work Sheet"): holograph (Box 227, Folder 4173)
      - "Old Dog"
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1982 Apr (Box 227, Folder 4174)
        - The Nation, 1983 Dec 3 (Box 227, Folder 4175)
      - "Old Flame" (Box 228, Folder 4176)
        - Holograph and typescript, carbon, [1977?]
        - Printed broadside
          See: Oversize, Box 315, folder 5359
      - "Old Love": typescript; carbon; and photocopy (Box 228, Folder 4177)
      - "Old Nigger on One-Mule Cart... ."
        - Holograph and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1975, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4178)
        - Setting typescript ( New Yorker ), 1978 (Box 228, Folder 4179)
        - Related correspondence (with explanatory letter by Warren), 1975 (Box 228, Folder 4180)
      - "Old Photograph of the Future": holograph and typescripts, corrected (various states), 1982 (Box 228, Folder 4181)
      - "Old-Time Childhood in Kentucky": holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1981 (Box 228, Folder 4182)
      - "Omen": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1982 (Box 228, Folder 4183)
      - "On Into The Night"
        See: Box 225, folder 4009
      - "One Way to Love God": holograph; typescript, corrected; and photocopy (Box 228, Folder 4184)
      - "The Only Poem": holograph and typescripts, corrected, 1978 (Box 228, Folder 4185)
      - "Or Dream": typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4186)
      - "Original Sin: A Short Story." Poetry in the Age of Anxiety (Fifth McGregor Room Seminar, University of Virginia): printed text, 1947 (Box 228, Folder 4187)
      - "Orphanage Boy": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 228, Folder 4188)
      - "Oxford City Wall" ("City Wall"): typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4189)
      - "Paradigm of Seasons": holograph; typescript, corrected; and carbons, 1982 (Box 228, Folder 4190)
      - "Paradox": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1975 (Box 228, Folder 4191)
      - "Paradox and Transience of Identity"
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1981 (Box 228, Folder 4192)
        - Final draft (with letter from New Yorker ): typescript, 1981 (Box 228, Folder 4193)
      - "Paradox of Time":
        - Typescripts and carbons, corrected (with letters from The New Yorkers ) (Box 228, Folder 4194)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1981 (Box 228, Folder 4195)
      - "Park Scene": typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4196)
      - "Part of a Short Story"
        - Holograph and early typescript (Box 228, Folder 4197)
        - Revised drafts: typescripts and carbons, corrected (various states), 1978-79 (Box 228, Folder 4198)
      - "Passersby on Snowy Night": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, 1978 (Box 228, Folder 4199)
      - "Patriotic Tour and Postulate of Joy": setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1966 Jan 22 (Box 228, Folder 4200)
      - "Picnic of Old Friends" ("The Distance Between"): holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected (with letter from The Sewanee Review ), 1981, 1984 (Box 228, Folder 4201)
      - "The Place"
        - Holograph and typescript, corrected, 1982 Jul (Box 228, Folder 4202)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1982 (Box 228, Folder 4203)
      - "Platonic Drowse": holograph and typescripts, carbon, 1929 (Box 228, Folder 4204)
      - "Platonic Lassitude": holograph, typescripts, and carbons, corrected (various states), 1982, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4205)
      - "Poem": holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1984, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4206)
      - "Portrait of Three Ladies": typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4207)
      - "Prairie Harvest": holograph and typescript, carbons, 1978 (Box 228, Folder 4208)
      - "Praise": holograph and typescript, 1926 (Box 228, Folder 4209)
      - "Praises for Mrs. Dodd Deceased": typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4210)
      - "Preternaturally Early Snowfall... .": setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1979 (Box 228, Folder 4211)
      - "Pro Sua Vita": typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4212)
      - "A Problem in Spatial Composition": holograph, typescripts, and carbons, corrected, 1973 (Box 228, Folder 4213)
      - "Problem of Autobiography... .": typescript, 1982 (Box 228, Folder 4214)
      - "Promises"
        - "Galley proofs, photocopy (incomplete), n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4215)
        - Encounter (with revisions), 1957 May (Box 228, Folder 4216)
      - "Prophecy"
        - The Mess Kit: photocopy, [1922] (Box 228, Folder 4217)
        - Printed broadside (Stuart Wright), 1980 (Box 228, Folder 4218)
      - "Pursuit": typescript, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4219)
      - "Question at Cliff-Thrust":
        - Holograph and typescript, carbon, 1982 Apr (Box 228, Folder 4220)
        - London Magazine (with revisions), 1984 Oct (Box 228, Folder 4221)
      - "Question You must Learn to Live Past"
        - Typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 228, Folder 4222)
        - Salmagundi (with revisions), 1980-1981 (Box 228, Folder 4223)
      - "Rather Like a Dream" ("Or Dream"): holograph and typescripts, corrected (Box 228, Folder 4224)
      - "Rattlesnake Country": holograph, typescript, and photocopies, corrected (Box 228, Folder 4225)
      - "Reading Late at Night"
        - Holograph, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4226)
        - Early typescript, corrected (with section marked "New #7" and letter from the The New Yorker ), 1973, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 4227)
        - Revised typescript, carbon, 1973 (Box 228, Folder 4228)
        - Revised typescript and carbon, corrected, 1973 (Box 228, Folder 4229)
        - Typescript, with comments by Allen Tate, [1973] (Box 228, Folder 4230)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1974 (Box 228, Folder 4231)
      - "Rebuke of the Rocks": broadside (American Poetry Society), 1976 (Box 229, Folder 4232)
      - "Recollection"
        - Holograph and typescript, carbons, 1984 (Box 229, Folder 4233)
        - Typescript, corrected (with letters from The New Yorker ), 1984 (Box 229, Folder 4234)
      - "Recollection from Boyhood Evening": holograph, typescript, and carbon, 1983 Feb (Box 229, Folder 4235)
      - "Recollection in Upper Ontario": holograph, typescripts, and carbons, corrected (various states), 1975-77 (Box 229, Folder 4236)
      - "Red-Tail Hawk and Pyre of Youth"
        - Holograph, 1977 Mar 15 (Box 229, Folder 4237)
        - Typescripts and carbons, corrected (various states) (Box 229, Folder 4238-39)
        - Typesetting copy
          - First version, 1977 Feb 8 (Box 229, Folder 4240)
          - Revised version, 1977 Jul 18 (Box 229, Folder 4241)
        - Printed text: photocopy, [1977] (Box 229, Folder 4242)
      - "Reinterment: Recollection of a Grandfather"
        - Original holograph and early typescripts, 1982, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4243)
        - Revised drafts: holograph and typescripts, corrected, 1982-83 (Box 229, Folder 4244)
      - "Remarks for Historians": holograph and typescripts, corrected, 1978 (Box 229, Folder 4245)
      - "The Return: An Elegy" (commentary): holograph and typescript (Box 229, Folder 4246)
      - "Revolution" ("At midnight or noontide... ."): holograph and typescript, 1981 (Box 229, Folder 4247)
      - "Riddle of the Dust": typescript, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4248)
      - "Roman Macabre": typescript, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4249)
      - "Rosanna": typescript, 1976 Aug (Box 229, Folder 4250)
      - "Rumor at Twilight"
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbons, 1981, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4251)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1982 (Box 229, Folder 4252)
      - "Safe in Shade": holograph and typescript, carbon, [1979] (Box 229, Folder 4253)
      - "San Francisco Night Windows": typescript (Box 229, Folder 4254)
      - "The Sea Hates the Land": typescript, 1980 Feb (Box 229, Folder 4255)
      - "Season Opens on Wild Boar in Chianti": holograph and typescript, carbon (with copy of letter from Warren), 1975 (Box 229, Folder 4256)
      - "Seasons": holograph, typescripts, and carbons, corrected (various states), 1982 (Box 229, Folder 4257)
      - "Self"
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbon, 1981, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4258)
        - The Nation (with corrections), 1983 May 7 (Box 229, Folder 4259)
      - "Sense of Direction": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1981 (Box 229, Folder 4260)
      - "September Day in the Mountains": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1981 Aug (Box 229, Folder 4261)
      - "September Twilight Piece": holograph, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4262)
      - "Several Days: Thursday": holograph, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4263)
      - "Shadows": holograph, 1988 Jul 19 (Box 229, Folder 4264)
      - "Shoes in Rain Jungle." The New York Review, 1965 Nov 11 (Box 229, Folder 4265)
      - "A Short Story That Could Be Longer": typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4266)
      - "Shutter Bangs All Night": holograph and typescript (various states), 1984 (Box 229, Folder 4267)
      - "Sila": holograph, typescripts, and carbon, corrected, 1978-79 (Box 229, Folder 4268-69)
      - "Sister Water"
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbon, 1976 (Box 229, Folder 4270)
        - Setting typescript ( New York Review of Books ), [1976] (Box 229, Folder 4271)
      - "Sitting on Farm Lawn on Sunday Afternoon"
        - Typescript, corrected ("final version"), 1980 May 20 (Box 229, Folder 4272)
        - Washington Post Magazine, 1980 Aug 3 (Box 229, Folder 4273)
      - "Sky"
        - Holograph and typescript, corrected, 1979 (Box 229, Folder 4274)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), [1980] (Box 229, Folder 4275)
      - "The Smile" ("Mellow, mellow, at thrush-hour"): holograph and typescript, corrected, 1977 (Box 229, Folder 4276)
      - "The Smile" ("Down the street while grunting hulk would shove... ."): holograph, typescript, and carbon, 1984 (Box 229, Folder 4277)
      - "Snowfall"
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected (various states), 1982, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4278)
        - Printed broadside, 1984 (Box 229, Folder 4279)
      - "Snow-Shoeing Back to Camp in Gloaming"
        - Holograph and early typescripts with carbons, 1978 (Box 229, Folder 4280)
        - Revised typescripts (various states), 1978 (Box 229, Folder 4281)
        - New England Review (with revisions), 1979 Spring (Box 229, Folder 4282)
      - "Social Notes": holograph, typescript, and carbon (Box 229, Folder 4283)
      - "Solipsism and Theology": setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1972 (Box 229, Folder 4284)
      - "Somewhere": holograph, typescripts and photocopy, 1977-78 (Box 229, Folder 4285)
      - "Sonnets of Two Summers": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4286)
      - "Speleology": holograph and typescript, corrected, 1978 (Box 229, Folder 4287)
      - "Spring off the Gulf": holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected (Box 229, Folder 4288)
      - "Star-Fall" (marked "rejected"): holograph and typescript, [1977] (Box 229, Folder 4289)
      - "Stop! War!": typescript, corrected, 1980 Aug (Box 229, Folder 4290)
      - "Summer Afternoons and Hypnosis": setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1980 (Box 229, Folder 4291)
      - "Sunday Afternoon in Summer in Old Barn": holograph, typescript, and carbons, 1981-82 (Box 229, Folder 4292)
      - "Sunset": holograph, typescript and carbon, 1982 (Box 229, Folder 4293)
      - "Sunset Scrupulously Observed"
        - Typescript, 1980 (Box 229, Folder 4294)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1981 (Box 229, Folder 4295)
      - "Swimming in the Pacific" ("Pacific Dream"): holograph, typescripts and carbons, corrected (various states), 1978, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 4296)
      - "Synonyms": holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, [1979] (Box 229, Folder 4297)
      - "Tale of Time"
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected (with comments by Allen Tate), [c.1966] (Box 230, Folder 4298)
        - Encounter (with corrections), 1966 Mar (Box 230, Folder 4299)
      - "Terror" (with comments by Allen Tate): typescript, [c.1941] (Box 230, Folder 4300)
      - "There's a Grandfather Clock in the Hall", [1976] (Box 230, Folder 4301)
      - "Three Darknesses" (incomplete): typescript, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4302)
      - "Time as Hypnosis"
        - Typescript, corrected (with comments by Allen Tate), [c.1973] (Box 230, Folder 4303)
        - Printed text (from I. A. Richards: Essays in His Honor ), 1973 (Box 230, Folder 4304)
      - "Timeless, Twinned": holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, [1979] (Box 230, Folder 4305)
      - "Tires on Wet Asphalt at Night": holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1978 (Box 230, Folder 4306)
      - "To One Awake." The New Republic, 1928 May 30 (Box 230, Folder 4307)
      - "To One Not Quite a Clown": typescript, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4308)
      - "Tramp" (incomplete): typescript, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4309)
      - "Trips to California": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1978 (Box 230, Folder 4310)
      - "True Love": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, 1981 (Box 230, Folder 4311)
      - "Truth": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, [1979] (Box 230, Folder 4312)
      - "Truth-Seeker, Half-Naked, at Night... .": holograph, typescripts, and carbons, corrected (various states), 1977 (Box 230, Folder 4313)
      - "Trying to Tell You Something"
        - Holograph and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 230, Folder 4314)
        - Setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1976 (Box 230, Folder 4315)
      - "Tulip-Tree in Bloom"
        - First draft: holograph; typescript, corrected; and carbon (Box 230, Folder 4316)
        - Revised version, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4317)
        - The Iowa Review (with revisions) (Box 230, Folder 4318)
      - "Twice Born" (with copy of letter from Sewanee Review ): typescript, photocopy, 1980 (Box 230, Folder 4319)
      - "Two Pieces After Suetonius" (with revisions). Partisan Review, 1958 Spring (Box 230, Folder 4320)
      - "Two Sonnets of Eternity": typescript, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4321)
      - "Uncertain Season in High Country" (original and revised versions): holograph and typescripts, corrected, 1984 (Box 230, Folder 4322)
      - "Unless": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, [1976] (Box 230, Folder 4323)
      - "Up and At 'Em, Ron": typescript, photocopy (Box 230, Folder 4324)
      - "Upwardness": holograph and typescript, 1984 (Box 230, Folder 4325)
      - "Upon Reading a Psalm": typescript and carbons (Box 230, Folder 4326)
      - "Vermont": holograph, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4327)
      - "Vermont Ballad: Change of Season": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4328)
      - "A Version of Identity" (with letter from Warren): holograph, typescript, and carbons, 1983 (Box 230, Folder 4329)
      - "Vision" ("The vision will come.. .")
        - Holograph, typescript, and carbons, 1978 (Box 230, Folder 4330)
        - Washington Post Book World, 1979 Aug 12 (Box 230, Folder 4331)
      - "Waiting"
        - Holograph and typescript, carbon, 1976 (Box 230, Folder 4332)
        - Galley proof ( Times Literary Supplement ), [1976] (Box 230, Folder 4333)
      - "Waking to Tap of Hammer": holograph and typescript, carbons, corrected, 1977 (Box 230, Folder 4334)
      - "Was It a Rough-Leg (Butco Lagopus)?"
        See: "Mortal Limit", Box 227, folder 4137
      - "Was It One of the 'Long Hunters' of Kentucky.. .?": typescript and carbons, corrected (Box 230, Folder 4335)
      - "Watch a Clock Closely": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 4336)
      - "Weather Report": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, [1978] (Box 230, Folder 4337)
      - "What Is The Voice That Speaks?": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, 1978-79 (Box 230, Folder 4338)
      - "What Voice at Moth Hour": setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1981 (Box 230, Folder 4339)
        Related Materials
        There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 334.
      - "What Voice at Moth Hour?", undated; 1; 00:03:26; The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 334, Item barcode 39002099360159)
        This audiocassette is related to material that can be found in Box 230.
      - "When Life Begins": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1979 (Box 230, Folder 4340)
      - "When the Tooth Cracks--Zing!": holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1976 (Box 230, Folder 4341)
      - "When Words Won't Come": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1981 (Box 230, Folder 4342)
      - "Where the Slow Fig's Purple Sloth": setting typescript ( The New Yorker ), 1967 (Box 230, Folder 4343)
      - "Whip-Poor-Will": holograph and typescript, carbon, [1983] (Box 230, Folder 4344)
      - "Whistle of the 3 A.M. Express": holograph, typescript, and carbons, corrected, 1981 (Box 230, Folder 4345)
      - "Who?": holograph, typescripts, and carbons, 1983 (Box 230, Folder 4346)
      - "The Whole Question": holographs, typescript, and carbon, 1981 (Box 230, Folder 4347)
      - "Why Boy Came to lonely Place": holograph, typescript, and carbon (Box 230, Folder 4348)
      - "Why Do I Love the Meaningless Things I Remember?": holograph; typescript, corrected; and carbons, 1978 (Box 230, Folder 4349)
      - "Why Have I Wandered the Asphalt of Midnight?" ("Why?"): holograph and typescripts, carbon, [1978] (Box 230, Folder 4350)
      - "Why You Climbed Up":
        - Holograph, typescripts, and carbons, corrected, 1982 (Box 230, Folder 4351)
        - The Georgia Review (with revisions), 1983 Fall (Box 230, Folder 4352)
      - "Wind and Gibbon" ("Wind")
        - Holograph and typescript (Box 231, Folder 4353)
        - Encounter (with corrections), 1985 Feb (Box 231, Folder 4354)
      - "Wind Changes": holograph and typescript, carbon, 1982 Feb (Box 231, Folder 4355)
      - "Winter Dreams": typescript and carbons, corrected (Box 231, Folder 4356)
      - "Winter Wheat: Oklahoma": holograph; typescripts, corrected; and carbons, 1982, n.d. (Box 231, Folder 4357)
      - "With or Without Compass": typescript and carbons, corrected, 1981-82 (Box 231, Folder 4358)
      - "The Wrestling Match": typescript and carbon, 1925 (Box 231, Folder 4359)
      - "You Sort Old Letters: typescript and carbons, corrected (Box 231, Folder 4360)
      - "Young Man in April Dusk": typescript, n.d. (Box 231, Folder 4361)
      - "Youth Stares at Minoan Sunset": holograph; typescript, corrected; carbon; and photocopy, 1976 (Box 231, Folder 4362)
      - "Youthful Picnic Long Ago: Sad Ballad on Box"
        - Holograph, typescripts, carbons, and photocopies (various states), 1981, n.d. (Box 231, Folder 4363)
        - Commentary by Warren: typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 231, Folder 4364)
      - Poem fragments (Box 231, Folder 4365-67)
      - Reading text of poems for Columbia recording: typescript, 1971 (Box 231, Folder 4368-69)
      - "Robert Penn Warren Reads Selected Poems, 1923-1978" :1 LP (Caedmon, TC 1654)
        Library of Congress #: 79-740862
        See: Oversize, Box 314, folder 5359a
    - Essays and Articles
      - "The American Tragedy" (introduction to Theodore Dreiser, An American Tragedy, World Publishing Co. edition)
        Draft A ("First Draft")
        - Copy 1: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4370)
        - Copy 2: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4371)
        - Draft B: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4372)
        - Draft C: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4373)
        - Draft D: typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4374)
        - Miscellaneous pages (marked "discarded leaves"): typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4375)
        - "Van Dykes" (for Yale Review reprinting?) (Box 232, Folder 4376)
        - Der amerikanische Roman im 19. und 20. Jahrhundert (offprint) (Box 232, Folder 4377)
      - "Andrew Lytle's The Long Night: A Rediscovery.": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 232, Folder 4378)
      - "The Briar Patch" (from I'll Take My Stand ): typescript (Box 232, Folder 4379)
      - "Brooks and Warren"
        - First draft: holograph, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4380)
        - Revised draft (marked "final copy"): typescript, corrected (with page revisions and inserts) (Box 232, Folder 4381)
        - Humanities, 1985 Apr (Box 232, Folder 4382)
      - [Brown, Elizabeth]. Untitled introduction (unpublished) to the letters of Elizabeth Brown, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4383)
      - [Bullock, Marie]. Tribute for Academy of American Poets: holograph, [1984] (Box 232, Folder 4384)
      - "Can Democracy Survive in a World of Technology?" U.S News and World Report (photocopy), 1980 Aug 18 (Box 232, Folder 4385)
      - [Cox, Hugh]. Tribute to Hugh B. Cox in The Perfect Advocate: A Memoir of the Late Hugh B. Cox, Esquire., n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4386)
      - "Daniel Boone of Boonesborough."
        See: "The World of Daniel Boone", Box 237, folder 4544
      - [Davidson, Donald]. Untitled essay on Donald Davidson: holograph and notebook (Box 232, Folder 4387)
      - "A Dearth of Heroes." Introduction to Dixon Wecter, The Hero in America: typescript, [1971] (Box 232, Folder 4388)
        See also: Box 233, folder 4410
      - [Eberhart, Richard]. Untitled essay on the poems of Richard Eberhart: holograph, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4389)
      - "Elizabeth Madox Roberts: Life Is from Within": typescript (marked "first draft"), n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4390)
      - "Episode in the Dime Store": typescript, corrected and carbons (Box 232, Folder 4391)
      - [Essays]. "Introduction to Essays in Russian": holograph, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4392)
      - "Faulkner: The South and the Negro" (with revisions). The Southern Review, Summer 1965 (Box 232, Folder 4393)
        See also: Oversize, Box 291, folders 5227-32
      - Fifty Years of American Poetry. Preface
        - Holograph, [1983] (Box 232, Folder 4394)
        - Typescript, corrected, [1983] (Box 232, Folder 4395)
      - "Flannery O'Connor--A Tribute." Esprit (University of Scranton), 1964 Winter (Box 232, Folder 4396)
      - "Function of Criticism" (incomplete): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4397)
      - "The Genius of Katherine Anne Porter": holograph, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4398)
      - [Gordon, Caroline]. The Collected Stories of Caroline Gordon.
        - Preface: holograph and typescript, carbon, [1980] (Box 232, Folder 4399)
        - Reviews, 1981 (Box 232, Folder 4400)
      - Grimshaw, James A. Robert Penn Warren: A Descriptive Bibliography, 1922-79. Preface: holograph and typescript (Box 232, Folder 4401)
      - "Hawthorne Revisited: Some Remarks on Hellfiredness."
        - Galley proofs: photocopy, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4402)
        - Galley proofs: photocopy,corrected, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 4403)